PAUL DAVIDSON WEB DEVELOPER

paulrossdavidson@gmail.com paulrossdavidson.github.io

♀ Seattle

in paul-davidson

PaulRossDavidson

With a passion for building web apps using the most simple, short and clear code solutions, Paul is gaining experience with Angular.js and other technologies to become a top teir developer. Paul looks forward to merging his interests in travel, outdoor recreation and new technologies with web based solutions at every chance he

When not coding, he enjoys DIY projects, economics and travelling.

Skills

FRONT END

Angular.js

HTML5

CSS Material

Pair Programming

BootStrap

JavaScript

BACK END

MongoDB

Node.js

Express

PostgreSQL

Ruby

Sails

Node.js

DEVELOPMENT

Git

Pair Programming

Education

University of Alaska, Anchorage BA 2011

Employment

General Assebly

Full Stack Web Developer

Seattle Jun 2015 to Sep 2015

This program fulfilled a long growing passion for web development through intensive, skills acquisition. For 12 weeks it was hands on project work 20 hours per week and learned cutting edge technology from experienced professionals for 40 hours per week in a startup/co-working space. This program gave me industry best practices from professionals.

GearSpoke

Anchorage, AK Mar 2011 to Apr 2014

CEO

Continuously improved company direction and site development by asking the right questions to potential users, looking at data, listening to mentors and becoming an expert in the sharing economy. Created, energized and managed a cohesive six person team with development and marketing sub teams. Built a high impact, low cost, marketing plan and owned it's execution. Created mutually beneficial marketing relationships with local companies. Put on events for target market. Presented the company and the sharing economy at local speaking events. Successfully implemented remote working days.

BP Oil Exploration

Buyer -Rotating Equipment

Anchorage, AK

Mar 2011 to Jun 2013

Worked as mid value buyer (25k-250k) for rotating equipment for BP Exploration Alaska. Utilized good communication to coordinate working with remote co-workers. Toured warehouses and local manufacturing spaces and met with various suppliers. Volunteered as the emergency response coordinator for the 6th floor at BP headquarters, completing a suite of training classes.

Projects

The Prepper Prepper App

An responsive web app to help people prepare for disasters based on their locations.

GearSpoke

GearSpoke is a P2P outdoor gear rental startup. Created with a team of seven people with Paul in the role of CEO, Paul drove the development and integration of user preferences into the site. The company was sold in March 2014.

Decider 3000

The Decider 3000 is a web app that helps people make big decisions in their lives and feel better about their results. At it's heart, it is an algorithm that compares what you value more about different options and gives you the best choice for you.

Asteroids

Asteroids is a fun, front end only game loosely inspired by the asteroid game. JQuiery is used in a clean, simple implementation to make a simple two player game.

Activities

DIY Drones · Hacker

Iul 2003 to Current

I build RC aircraft out of recycled junk and cheap electronics. I do aerial photography and have a lot of fun.